[
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "How old was Joseph when his brethren sold him into slavery?",
    "options": [
      "32",
      "23",
      "17",
      "19"
    ],
    "answer": "17"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "How old was Moses when he gave God\u2019s message to Pharaoh: \u201cLet my people go\u201d?",
    "options": [
      "80 years",
      "18 years",
      "13 years",
      "33 years"
    ],
    "answer": "80 years"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "When Saul was pursuing David, in which cave did David seek refuge?",
    "options": [
      "Cave at Makkedah",
      "Cave of Machpelah",
      "Cave of Adullam",
      "Dambulla Cave"
    ],
    "answer": "Cave of Adullam"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "According to 2 Kings 19, what king was killed by his own sons?",
    "options": [
      "Manasseh",
      "Sennacherib",
      "Ahaz",
      "Jotham"
    ],
    "answer": "Sennacherib"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "What aged prophet\u2019s hands were upheld by two persons and caused the armies of Israel to be victorious?",
    "options": [
      "Elisha",
      "Elijah",
      "Moses",
      "Hosea"
    ],
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "What queen of Bible times is described by the epithet \u201cthat wicked woman\u201d?",
    "options": [
      "Gomer",
      "Herodias",
      "Athaliah",
      "Jezebel"
    ],
    "answer": "Athaliah"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "In the stories of Samuel, which is not true?",
    "options": [
      "His mother was called Hannah",
      "He anointed 3 kings of Israel: Joseph, Saul, and David",
      "He succeeded the prophet Eli",
      "He had a vision while he was still very young"
    ],
    "answer": "He anointed 3 kings of Israel: Joseph, Saul, and David"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "What was the name of the city founded by Cain after he left God's presence?",
    "options": [
      "Sodom",
      "Gomorrah",
      "Enoch",
      "Canaan"
    ],
    "answer": "Enoch"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Which of Jesus' parables talks about God's forgiveness?",
    "options": [
      "Parable of the Tares and the Wheat",
      "Parable of the Ten Virgins",
      "Parable of the Prodigal Son",
      "Parable of the Good Samaritan",
      "Parable of the Sower"
    ],
    "answer": "Parable of the Prodigal Son"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who was the wise woman who stopped David from destroying Nabal, her husband, and her house?",
    "options": [
      "Merab",
      "Michal",
      "Abigail",
      "Bathsheba"
    ],
    "answer": "Abigail"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Which prophet made the iron of an axe float?",
    "options": [
      "Elijah",
      "Elisha",
      "Isaiah",
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "answer": "Elisha"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who resurrected a young man called Eutychus?",
    "options": [
      "Jesus",
      "Peter",
      "Philip",
      "Paul",
      "John"
    ],
    "answer": "Paul"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Can this phrase be found in the Bible? 'Pride goes before destruction'",
    "options": [
      "Yes",
      "No"
    ],
    "answer": "Yes"
  },
  {
    "type": "paragraph",
    "question": "Finish this proverb: 'Where there is no vision, . . . ;'",
    "answer": "The people perish"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who delivered Israel by killing 600 Philistines with an ox goad?",
    "options": [
      "David",
      "Jonathan",
      "Shamgar",
      "Samson"
    ],
    "answer": "Shamgar"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who heard Peter's voice at the door but failed to let him in?",
    "options": [
      "Martha",
      "Priscilla",
      "Lydia",
      "Rhoda"
    ],
    "answer": "Rhoda"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "What was Priscilla's trade?",
    "options": [
      "Seller of purple fabric",
      "Tent maker",
      "Idol maker",
      "Dressmaker"
    ],
    "answer": "Tent maker"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who suggested that Joseph interpret the dreams of Pharaoh?",
    "options": [
      "Potiphar",
      "The cupbearer",
      "Judah",
      "The baker"
    ],
    "answer": "The cupbearer"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "What was the total number of the children of Israel that went down to Egypt with Jacob?",
    "options": [
      "1000",
      "70",
      "53",
      "560"
    ],
    "answer": "70"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "What was Solomon\u2019s other name?",
    "options": [
      "Jedidiah",
      "Hezekiah",
      "Joab",
      "Sylvester"
    ],
    "answer": "Jedidiah"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who partook of a meal prepared by an angel, and was sustained forty days and nights while in the mountain?",
    "options": [
      "Manoah",
      "Joseph",
      "Elijah",
      "Moses"
    ],
    "answer": "Elijah"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who was the young woman who gave water to Eliezer and his camels in Mesopotamia?",
    "options": [
      "Milcah",
      "Rachel",
      "Ruth",
      "Rebekah"
    ],
    "answer": "Rebekah"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Hosea is to Gomer as Lapidoth is to",
    "options": [
      "Deborah",
      "Anna",
      "Keturah",
      "Hagar"
    ],
    "answer": "Deborah"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who was David\u2019s son that started a rebellion against him?",
    "options": [
      "Absalom",
      "Anna",
      "Keturah",
      "Hagar"
    ],
    "answer": "Absalom"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "True or False: Jesus was an only child of Joseph and Mary",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "False"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Which book of the Bible tells the story of the Israelites' escape from Egypt?",
    "options": [
      "Genesis",
      "Exodus",
      "Leviticus",
      "Numbers"
    ],
    "answer": "Exodus"
  },
  {
    "type": "paragraph",
    "question": "Complete the following, 'The light of the body is...'",
    "answer": "The eye"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "A piece of his robe was cut off in a cave. To whom did it belong?",
    "options": [
      "Nathan",
      "Saul",
      "Samuel",
      "Peter"
    ],
    "answer": "Saul"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who was Tola in the Bible?",
    "options": [
      "Judge",
      "King",
      "Prophet",
      "Priest"
    ],
    "answer": "Judge"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who had his wages changed ten times?",
    "options": [
      "Jacob",
      "David",
      "Moses",
      "Joseph"
    ],
    "answer": "Jacob"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Moses saw the burning bush on Mount Ararat.",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "False"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Blessed are the peacemakers, for",
    "options": [
      "They shall see God",
      "Theirs is the kingdom of God",
      "They shall know peace",
      "They shall be called the sons of God"
    ],
    "answer": "They shall be called the sons of God"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "King Cyrus was ruler of which nation?",
    "options": [
      "Egypt",
      "Babylon",
      "Persia",
      "Assyria"
    ],
    "answer": "Persia"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Where did Jesus cure the blind Bartimaeus?",
    "options": [
      "Bethany",
      "Jerusalem",
      "Nazareth",
      "Jericho"
    ],
    "answer": "Jericho"
  },
  {
    "type": "paragraph",
    "question": "We are to carry the shield of ...... (Fill in the blank)",
    "answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who was Agabus?",
    "options": [
      "King",
      "Prophet",
      "Apostle",
      "Tax collector"
    ],
    "answer": "Prophet"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Joseph, Reuben, Isaac and Levi. Who is the odd one out?",
    "options": [
      "Joseph",
      "Reuben",
      "Isaac",
      "Levi"
    ],
    "answer": "Isaac"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Abihu, Ithamar, Nadab and Phinehas. Who is the odd one out?",
    "options": [
      "Abihu",
      "Ithamar",
      "Phinehas",
      "Nadab"
    ],
    "answer": "Phinehas"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Apart from Jesus, who else walked on water?",
    "options": [
      "Nicodemus",
      "Peter",
      "Nathanael",
      "Paul"
    ],
    "answer": "Peter"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "What was the name of Aaron\u2019s (Moses\u2019s brother) wife?",
    "options": [
      "Elisheba",
      "Miriam",
      "Zipporah",
      "Deborah"
    ],
    "answer": "Elisheba"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "How many Philistines did Samson slay with a jaw bone?",
    "options": [
      "1,000",
      "550",
      "700",
      "2,000"
    ],
    "answer": "1,000"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "What is the name of the city to which Lot escaped at the destruction of Sodom?",
    "options": [
      "Golon",
      "Zoar",
      "Silo",
      "Cabul"
    ],
    "answer": "Zoar"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "As for me and my household, we will serve the LORD. Who said these words?",
    "options": [
      "Moses",
      "Paul",
      "Gideon",
      "Joshua"
    ],
    "answer": "Joshua"
  },
  {
    "type": "paragraph",
    "question": "Apart from John and Judas, name one disciple of Jesus that begins with letter J",
    "answer": "James"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Bernice can be connected with who?",
    "options": [
      "King Puri",
      "King Agrippa",
      "King Asa",
      "King Festus"
    ],
    "answer": "King Agrippa"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Out of his belly shall flow rivers of living water. Who spoke these words?",
    "options": [
      "Paul",
      "Prophet Isaiah",
      "Jesus",
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "answer": "Jesus"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "How many human couples entered Noah's ark?",
    "options": [
      "4 couples",
      "1 couple",
      "6 couples",
      "3 couples"
    ],
    "answer": "4 couples"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "What prophet was lifted between earth and heaven by a lock of his hair?",
    "options": [
      "Daniel",
      "Ezekiel",
      "Joel",
      "Elisha"
    ],
    "answer": "Ezekiel"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "What woman in the New Testament continued in prayer day and night in the temple?",
    "options": [
      "Priscilla",
      "Mary",
      "Anna",
      "Lydia"
    ],
    "answer": "Anna"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "What was the name of the wife of Joseph (son of Jacob)?",
    "options": [
      "Potiphera",
      "Zipporah",
      "Keturah",
      "Asenath"
    ],
    "answer": "Asenath"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who was the cupbearer to King Artaxerxes?",
    "options": [
      "Meshach",
      "Nehemiah",
      "Azariah",
      "Ezra"
    ],
    "answer": "Nehemiah"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "What was the name of the servant who had his ear cut off during Jesus\u2019 arrest?",
    "options": [
      "Titus",
      "Archipus",
      "Malchus",
      "Claudia"
    ],
    "answer": "Malchus"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "What city did Paul escape in a basket lowered from the wall?",
    "options": [
      "Tropas",
      "Antioch",
      "Malta",
      "Damascus"
    ],
    "answer": "Damascus",
    "is_tiebreaker": true
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who wrote, 'Vanity of vanities, all is vanity'?",
    "options": [
      "Job",
      "Solomon",
      "David",
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "answer": "Solomon"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who received two talents of silver and two sets of clothing from Naaman?",
    "options": [
      "Elisha",
      "Phinehas",
      "Gehazi",
      "Elijah"
    ],
    "answer": "Gehazi"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Ezekiel ate the scroll. What did the scroll taste like?",
    "options": [
      "Sour as lemon",
      "Sweet as honey",
      "Bitter as bile",
      "Hot and spicy"
    ],
    "answer": "Sweet as honey"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "As recorded in the Bible, who had 70 sons?",
    "options": [
      "Adam",
      "Lamech",
      "Gideon",
      "David"
    ],
    "answer": "Gideon"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who killed 30 men, just to get their garments?",
    "options": [
      "David",
      "Ahab",
      "Samson",
      "Joab"
    ],
    "answer": "Samson"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "To what did Jesus compare his disciples?",
    "options": [
      "Peppers",
      "Mint",
      "Salt",
      "Cinnamon"
    ],
    "answer": "Salt"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who sacrificed his own daughter because of his vow?",
    "options": [
      "Saul",
      "Jehu",
      "Shimei",
      "Jephthah"
    ],
    "answer": "Jephthah"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "A parable speaks of a woman who swept her entire house to find just one of how many silver coins?",
    "options": [
      "7",
      "10",
      "20",
      "25"
    ],
    "answer": "10"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Which city did Jonah flee towards to escape from the presence of the LORD?",
    "options": [
      "Tarshish",
      "Damascus",
      "Ekron",
      "Tarsus"
    ],
    "answer": "Tarshish"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "What seed did Manna look like?",
    "options": [
      "Mustard",
      "Barley",
      "Coriander",
      "Rice"
    ],
    "answer": "Coriander"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Which one of his 10 brothers did Joseph hold captive when they returned after their first trip to Egypt?",
    "options": [
      "Asher",
      "Reuben",
      "Judah",
      "Simeon"
    ],
    "answer": "Simeon"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Which book has 50 chapters?",
    "options": [
      "Exodus",
      "Genesis",
      "Numbers",
      "Leviticus"
    ],
    "answer": "Genesis"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Whose son was Jonah?",
    "options": [
      "Hilkiah",
      "Eliab",
      "Amittai",
      "Eleazar"
    ],
    "answer": "Amittai",
    "is_tiebreaker": true
  },
  {
    "type": "paragraph",
    "question": "Sanctify them through thy ______: thy word is ______.",
    "answer": "Truth"
  },
  {
    "type": "paragraph",
    "question": "Name Goliath's place of origin as mentioned in 1 Samuel.",
    "answer": "Gath"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who tied a scarlet cord in their window to ensure no harm would come to them when Israel attacked?",
    "options": [
      "Leah",
      "Michal",
      "Rahab",
      "Abigail"
    ],
    "answer": "Rahab"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Which gospel book's authorship is associated with a tax collector?",
    "options": [
      "Matthew",
      "Mark",
      "Luke",
      "John"
    ],
    "answer": "Matthew",
    "is_tiebreaker": true
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who was Leah's servant?",
    "options": [
      "Bilhah",
      "Abigail",
      "Zilpah",
      "Deborah"
    ],
    "answer": "Zilpah"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Which brothers were known as 'Boanerges'?",
    "options": [
      "Judas and Bartholomew",
      "Thomas and Philip",
      "James and John",
      "Peter and Andrew"
    ],
    "answer": "James and John"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "According to 1 John 1, who is God?",
    "options": [
      "Love",
      "Light",
      "Peace",
      "Shelter"
    ],
    "answer": "Light",
    "is_tiebreaker": true
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Who raised Tabitha (Dorcas) from the dead?",
    "options": [
      "James",
      "Peter",
      "Paul",
      "Jesus"
    ],
    "answer": "Peter"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "How many chapters are there in the book of Matthew?",
    "options": [
      "31",
      "29",
      "28",
      "17"
    ],
    "answer": "28"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "Jesus wept when Bartimaeus died.",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "False"
  },
  {
    "type": "mcq",
    "question": "What did God create on the fourth day according to Genesis?",
    "options": ["Plants and trees", "Sun, moon, and stars", "Animals and birds", "The seas and dry land"],
    "answer": "Sun, moon, and stars"
  }
]